Guide to the Sid Ramin Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series XIV: The Red Shoes
  - Subseries XIV.1 Lead Sheets
    Printed lead sheets with music by Jule Styne and lyrics by Marsha Norman. These lead sheets may have been used for the orchestration of the show by Sid Ramin and William D. Brohn.
    - The Rag (I-2-16), (6 Pages ) (Box Flat Box 717)
    - Audition Dance (Act I) I Forgot My Music (I-3-24), (6 Pages ) (Box Flat Box 717)
    - It's Always Like the First Time - Revised (I-3-27), 28 December 1992, (9 Pages ) (Box Flat Box 717)
    - La Valse - Solo Dance for Helen (I-5-37) [2 copies], (2 Pages ) (Box Flat Box 717)
    - Little Kitten (I-6-41), (7 Pages ) (Box Flat Box 717)
    - Red Shoes Story, (4 Pages ) (Box Flat Box 717)
    - Red Shoes Story (I-9-51), 1 December 1992, (7 Pages ) (Box Flat Box 717)
    - One - Two (I-11-61), (3 Pages ) (Box Flat Box 717)
    - I'll Never Know (I-12-65), (5 Pages ) (Box Flat Box 717)
    - Dos Vedanya (II-4-12), (6 Pages ) (Box Flat Box 717)
    - In Ultimo Sospira (II-7-25), (1 Page ) (Box Flat Box 717)
    - I'm Home (II-9-34), (2 Pages ) (Box Flat Box 717)
    - Pas De Deux (Act II) - Revised [2 copies], 28 April 1989, (16 Pages ) (Box Flat Box 717)
    - Red Shoes Ballet - Insert (Fighting R.S. Spell), (3 Pages ) (Box Flat Box 717)
    - The Red Shoes Fit (Dance) - Revised [3 copies], 28 April 1989, (9 Pages ) (Box Flat Box 717)
    - [Untitled], (6 Pages ) (Box Flat Box 717)
  - Subseries XIV.2 Sketches
    Original manuscript sketches used in preparation of the score with notations and corrections.
    - Sketches from Act I: Swan Lake Opening; The Impressario; To Lermontov's Office-I; Julian's Audition; To Lady Neston's; Nostrovya, Nostrovya; Class Before Audition-I; Class Before Audition-II; Three Girls Audition; To Craster's Flat; To Lermontov's Office-II; Swan Lake Pas de Deux; Top of the Sky; A Little Chopin; Montage [2 versions]; It's a Fairytale; When It Happens to You (Reprise); Be Somewhere; Am I to Wish Her Love, September-October 1993, (75 Pages ) (Box Flat Box 718)
    - Sketches from Act II: Do Svedanya; Am I to Wish Her Love Reprise (Miss Page); Miss Page; Tribute to Victoria Page; Alone in the Light; Come Home; When You Dance For a King; Ballet of the Red Shoes; Bows, September-October 1993, (104 Pages ) (Box Flat Box 718)
  - Subseries XIV.3 Scores of Original Orchestrations
    The scores of the original orchestrations arranged by Sid Ramin and William D. Brohn.
    - Overture Intro, 24 November 1993, (70 Pages 279, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 718)
    - Overture (Original Version), (78 Pages 304, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 718)
    - Overture (Revised Version), 8 November 1993, (70 Pages 279, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 718)
    - Overture (Proposed Ending), (4 Pages ) (Box Flat Box 718)
    - Swan Lake Opening, (18 Pages 74, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 718)
    - The Impressario, (19 Pages 75, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 718)
    - Vicky's Audition, (17 Pages 66, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 718)
    - Corps de Ballet - Part I, (33 Pages 132, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 718)
    - Corps de Ballet - Part II, (75 Pages 299, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 718)
    - When It Happens To You, (17 Pages 67, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 718)
    - When It Happens To You - Utility, (10 Pages 38, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 718)
    - Top of the Sky - New, (18 Pages 75, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 718)
    - Top of the Sky - New (11/17 Version), (24 Pages 75, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 718)
    - Montage, (36 Pages 242, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 719)
    - It's a Fairytale, (27 Pages 102, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 719)
    - Apres Cafe, (8 Pages 48, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 719)
    - The Dress Rehearsal, (17 Pages 63, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 719)
    - Be Somewhere, 10 November 1993, (15 Pages 60, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 719)
    - Be Somewhere - Utility, (11 Pages 43, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 719)
    - Grisha's Party Rag, (47 Pages 188, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 719)
    - Grisha's Rag - 151 to the end, (11 Pages Pages 37 to 47.) (Box Flat Box 719)
    - Am I to Wish Her Love, 10 November 1993, (33 Pages 104, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 719)
    - Do Svedanya, (12 Pages 48, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 719)
    - Who Knows Where It Goes, (11 Pages 44, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 719)
    - Tribute to Victoria Page, (16 Pages 64, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 719)
    - Alone in the Light, (15 Pages 58, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 719)
    - Come Home, (24 Pages 93, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 719)
    - Come Home - New, (21 Pages 82, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 719)
    - When You Dance For a King, (18 Pages 82, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 719)
    - Vicky's Exit, (2 Pages 7, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 719)
    - Heart of Fire, (16 Pages 66, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 719)
    - In the Dressing Room, (8 Pages 31, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 719)
    - Vicky Goes Mad, (3 Pages 10, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 719)
    - Vicky's Finale, (11 Pages 52, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 719)
    - The Ballet of the Red Shoes - Opening, (19 Pages 77, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 719)
    - The Ballet of the Red Shoes - Soliloquy [2 copies], (5 Pages 35, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 719)
    - The Ballet of the Red Shoes - Shoemaker's Dance, 11 October 1993, (27 Pages 97, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 719)
    - The Ballet of the Red Shoes - In the Shoeshop, (15 Pages 62, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 719)
    - The Ballet of the Red Shoes - Village, (10 Pages 39, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 720)
    - The Ballet of the Red Shoes - Village II, 11 October 1993, (10 Pages 39, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 720)
    - The Ballet of the Red Shoes - The Dance of the Red Shoes, (33 Pages 133, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 720)
    - The Ballet of the Red Shoes - Forest (Pas de Deux), (38 Pages 149, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 720)
    - The Ballet of the Red Shoes - Crazed Shoes, (13 Pages 50, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 720)
    - The Ballet of the Red Shoes - Gypsies, (18 Pages 144, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 720)
    - The Ballet of the Red Shoes - Cemetary, (19 Pages 73, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 720)
    - The Ballet of the Red Shoes - Finale, (15 Pages 59, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 720)
    - Bows, 9 November 1993, (30 Pages 116, Bars ) (Box Flat Box 720)
    - Exit Music, (23 Pages ) (Box Flat Box 720)